本字幕首发于字幕组网站
www.ZiMuZu.tv 欢迎交流
打开微信   扫描左侧二维码
或搜索公众号:    ustvboom
了解最新影视字幕发布信息
翻译：feilixiaozi  CS漫画家小明  潇湘月影  香茗小焙  木浅薰
翻译：王大可  某羽  杳杳  杨一勾  校对：油炸电风扇   潇湘月影
时间轴：Spohy    永远的永远
后期：斯人      总监：某羽
诉 讼 双 雄
第五季   第二集
《诉讼双雄》前情提要
-我要离开你了  哈维  -不能就这样辞职
- I'm leaving you, Harvey. - You can't just quit.
我不是要辞职
I'm not quitting.
我要去为路易工作
I'm going to work for Louis.
你要想治好失眠
Your sleepless nights aren't going to stop
就必须接受
until you accept the fact
你的秘书不会再回来这个事实
that your secretary isn't coming back.
我也说了  等她回来了  我就不会再失眠了
And I told you they'll stop when she does.
这是给你的正式通知  但我不会立刻
This is my formal notice, but I have no intention
把你晾下  所以我们还是讨论一下
of leaving you high and dry, so let's talk about
在两周内为你找一个新秘书吧
finding you someone in the next two weeks.
那你知道怎样对我最好吗
Do you know what's best for me?
-直面伤痛  -哈维
- Ripping the Band-Aid off. - Harvey--
所以你还是赶快收拾你的东西
So why don't you clean out your desk
搬去路易那里吧
and walk yourself over to Louis?
哈维  如果你对唐娜的事有任何不愉快...
Hey, Harvey, if there are any hard feelings with Donna--
不  路易  没有不愉快
No, Louis, no hard feelings.
但我只想说  如果万一有...
Okay, but I just want to say if there were--
我说了  没有
I said there's no hard feelings.
杰克・索罗夫正在律所里到处说
Jack Soloff has been going around the firm
你不可能挽救那家公司
saying you're never gonna save that company.
你什么时候开始在乎杰克・索罗夫说什么了
Since when do you care so much about what Jack Soloff says?
自从他成了一个有野心的资深合伙人
Since he's a senior partner with ambition.
我今天给你父亲打过电话了
I called your father today.
瑞秋・伊丽莎白・赞恩  你愿意嫁给我吗
Rachel Elizabeth Zane, will you marry me?
愿意
Yes.
为什么我就没权利挑吃饭的地方呢
How come I never get to pick the places we eat?
因为我不想吃鸡块当晚餐
Because I don't want chicken nuggets for dinner,
你也能少吃点那些东西
and you could take a break from them yourself.
但是在这块鸭肝慕斯上
I don't see a little healthy heart
我也没看到健康的心脏
next to this duck liver mousse.
真幽默  我让迈克试了
Very funny. I got Mike to try it.
妻管严这事我可帮不上忙
I can't help it if the man is whipped.
说到这  让我看看你妈妈一直念叨的
Speaking of which, let me see that ring
那个戒指
your mother keeps talking about.
好吧  看来他很清楚自己在干什么
Okay. I guess he knows what he's doing.
他要娶我了  所以  显然如此
Well, he's marrying me, so obviously.
既然说到这儿了
While we're on the topic...
-这是婚前协议  -是的  我让汤姆起草的
- This is a prenup. - Yeah. I had Tom draw it up.
其实就是一份标准化的协议
It's actually a standard boilerplate--
我不想让自己的婚姻
I don't wanna start my marriage
以规划如何结束为起点
planning how it's going to end.
瑞秋  婚前协议不是这个作用
Rachel, that is not what a prenup is for,
你也知道这点
and you know that.
是为了隔离资产  以保护你自己
It's to isolate assets in order to protect yourself.
我没有什么资产可以保护
I don't have assets to protect.
你有的
Yes, you do.
好吧
Right.
你是说你的钱
You're talking about your money.
自从我大学毕业
I haven't taken a dime from you
就没有要过你的一分钱
since the day I graduated from college.
是啊  或许是没有
Yeah, maybe not,
但总有一天你会得到我的全部身家
but one day you're gonna get everything I have.
爸爸
Dad--
瑞秋  到处都有人在离婚
Rachel, marriages end all the time,
我只想确保你得到应有的保护
and I just want to make sure that you're taken care of,
万一你和迈克出了什么问题
if something goes wrong between you and Mike.
万一我和迈克出了什么问题
If something goes wrong between me and Mike,
我会得到保护  因为迈克不会
I will be taken care of, because Mike wouldn't--
-这可说不准  -你不了解迈克
- You don't know that. - You don't know Mike.
你说得对  我是不了解  所以我才起草了协议
You're right, I don't, which is why I had that drawn up,
你至少可以把它带回家看一看
and the least you could do is take it home and look it over.
好吧
Fine.
现在我们能享受余下的晚餐时光了吗
Now, can we enjoy the rest of our dinner together?
尽量吧
We can try.
大迈克
Big Mike.
-太久没见了  -太久了
- It's been too long. - Too long.
也许我们都太忙于
Guess we're just too busy
在牛逼律所当牛逼助理律师了
being kickass associates at kickass law firms.
我不知道你怎样  但我有时候牛逼
I don't know about you, but some days I kick ass...
有时候
And some days...
有时候傻逼
You get your ass kicked.
好了  迈克  有什么重要消息
Okay, Mike, so what is this big news?
你是以最快速成为初级合伙人了吗
You the fastest person ever to make it to junior partner?
-更好  我订婚了  -不是吧
- Better. I got engaged. - No shit.
是的
Yes shit.
她从哪个国家来
Well, what country is she from?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我猜她应该是个邮寄新娘
Well, I'm assuming she's a mail-order bride.
好吧
Okay.
是瑞秋・赞恩
It's Rachel Zane.
-真的吗  -真的
- Damn. - Mm-hmm.
祝贺你  伙计
Congratulations, bro.
说真的  你真的是中了头彩
Seriously, you hit the jackpot with that one.
谢谢  吉米
Thank you, Jimmy.
等等  哈罗德知道吗
Wait--wait a second, does Harold know?
不知道  所以我才叫你们过来
No, that's why I brought you guys down here.
好吧  那你知道他非常喜欢她吧
Okay. You do know he has a huge crush on her, right?
-多喜欢  -迈克  行了吧
- How huge? - Mike, come on.
我们说的是哈罗德  你认为呢
We're talking about Harold here. What do you think?
-糟了  -伙计们  大家都好呀
- Oh, shit. - Hey, bros, what's the haps?
-你好  -你好
- Hey. - Hey.
我来告诉你发生了什么事  哈罗德
I will tell you the haps, Harold.
-你记得瑞秋・赞恩吗  -当然记得了
- Do you remember Rachel Zane? - Uh, yeah, of course.
我现在还每天查看她的脸书页面十来次
I still check her Facebook page, like, ten times a day.
怎么了  她出什么事了吗
Why? Did something bad happen to her?
如果我是她  我确实认为这事很糟
Well, if I was her, I would think it was bad.
事实上  是糟透了
In fact, I'd think it really sucked.
瑞秋和我订婚了
Rachel and I got engaged.
那太好了
Oh, that's amazing.
我太为你高兴了
I am so happy for you, man. Wow.
真的吗  你看起来不高兴
Really? 'Cause you sure don't look happy.
吉米  你去给哈罗德拿杯喝的吧
Hey, Jimmy, why don't you go get Harold a drink?
-我不去怎么样  -等等  迈克
- Why don't I don't? - Wait a second, Mike.
你记得那次我在档案室
Do you remember that time when I walked in on you
碰到你和唐娜・鲍尔森
and Donna Paulsen in the file room,
而她跪在地上
and she was on her knees?
说实话吧  我们都知道发生了什么
Let's be honest, we all know what was going on there.
瑞秋知道这事吗
Does Rachel know about that?
她不仅知道  而且完全接受
Not only does she know, she's totally fine with it.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
你真是全世界最幸运的人
You are the luckiest man in the entire freaking world.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
气死我了  我需要找个服务员
Pissing me off. I need my waitress.
-得来杯迈泰鸡尾酒 -恩  去找她吧
- I need a Mai Tai. - Yeah, go get her.
迈泰酒  他需要的是跟女人滚床单
Mai Tai? He needs some sex from a woman.
我想咖啡没有给我的
I don't suppose one of those would be for me.
就算有  我猜你也不想要
I don't think you'd want it if it was.
因为路易喜欢加六块糖
Louis likes six sugars.
肯定的
Of course he does.
我听说你今天上午要给接替我的人面试
I hear you're interviewing replacements this morning.
没错
I am.
杰克・索罗夫
Jack Soloff.
你来我这干什么
What brings you to my neck of the woods?
为见你
You do.
是不是跟
Oh, does this have anything to do
杰西卡不参加明天的合伙人会议有关系
with Jessica not being at the partners meeting tomorrow?
当然
It sure does.
那我比你行动早多了  她不明白
Oh, well, then I'm way ahead of you. She doesn't get it.
我们必须在男洗手间装通风设备
We need ventilation in the men's bathroom.
今天早上  我在尼尔・斯维邱之后进去
I was in there after Neil Sweetzer this morning,
我的双眼差点从脸上融化掉
and my eyes, they nearly melted off my face.
那确实是个问题
That is a problem.
但不是我来找你的原因
Not why I'm here.
我是想更改公司的薪金方案
I'd like to alter the firm's compensation formula.
好吧杰克  听着  我知道
Okay, Jack, look, I know that
我知道你是薪金委员会的新任领导
you're the new head of the compensation committee,
-我觉得这不是好主意  -薪水应该
- but I don't think that's a good idea. - Salaries should be
更多地取决于小时佣金收入而不是胜诉酬金
weighted more towards billables than contingent compensation.
你觉得呢
What do you think about that?
我觉得这对哈维的薪水影响最大
I think that affects Harvey's salary more than anyone else's.
是吗
Would it?
-我没注意到  -胡扯
- Hadn't realized. - Bullshit.
你在利用职权向哈维发难
You're using your position to take on Harvey.
想扬名立万总得找人发难
Hey, you don't make a name for yourself taking on nobody.
你愿意我找上你吗
Would you rather it be you?
你在威胁我吗
You threatening me?
我为什么要威胁你
Why would I do that?
路易  你是冠名合伙人  因为你劳苦功高
Louis, you're a name partner. Got there by being a grinder.
劳苦功高的人分得更大的利益
It's only fair that the grinders of this firm
才算公平
got a bigger piece of the pie.
另外  杰西卡不会
On top of that, Jessica's not gonna be
出席明天的会议
at the meeting tomorrow.
天赐良机
Timing couldn't be better.
你提案吧
You know what? Bring it up.
谢谢  路易
Thank you, Louis.
怎么回事
What was that?
-什么怎么回事  -那个
- What was what? - That.
那是杰克・索罗夫想让我批准他提出提案
That was Jack Soloff wanting to run his proposal by me.
是的  一个为了给哈维减薪的鬼提案
Yeah. A bullshit proposal designed to cut Harvey's salary.
你又要跟他斗
You're picking a fight with him.
我没有
No, I'm not.
我让在会上他提出这个提案
I'm letting him bring up his proposal at the meeting,
这样我就可以否决它
so I can smack it down.
为什么要这么做
Why would you do that?
因为我看到哈维的眼神
Because I saw the look on Harvey's face.
他嫉妒我们
He's jealous of us,
而我希望有机会公开支持他
and I want the chance to back him publicly.
路易  哈维也许对我们很不爽
Louis, Harvey might be upset about us,
但鼓励别人阴他
but encouraging people to go after him
就为了你能支持他  绝对是个大错误
just so you can have his back is a huge mistake.
你在米尔斯顿・斯维工作了七年
You were at Millstein Swain for seven years.
艾伦・斯维退休后  我决定换个东家
When Ellen Swain retired, I decided it was time to move on.
为什么不找律所的其他合伙人
Why not go to another partner in the firm?
因为我觉得其他合伙人
Because I didn't think any of the other partners
不够好
were good enough.
我感谢你的诚实
I appreciate the honesty.
我也感谢你第一个叫我进来
And I appreciate being the first person you called in,
如果你真想传闻中说的善于识人
and if you're as good at reading people as they say,
我也会是最后一个进来的人
I'll also be the last.
-真的吗  -你可以试试
- Is that a fact? - Call anyone you want.
我是法律秘书中的迪昂・桑德斯[橄榄球星]
I'm the Deion Sanders of legal secretaries.
-迪昂・桑德斯  -我办事动作快
- Deion Sanders? - I'm quick on my feet.
知道如何阻止问题发生
I know how to intercept a problem.
是的  但是迪昂・桑德斯
Yeah, but Deion Sanders?
如果你想换个时代  那我是迪克・巴克斯[老一代球星]
If you prefer another era, Dick Butkus.
总之  无人能出我之右
Either way, no one gets by me.
你看上去可不像迪克・巴克斯
You don't look like Dick Butkus.
确实不像
No, I don't.
谢谢  阿比盖尔  我会联系你的
Well, thanks, Abigail. I'll be in touch.
你
You.
你当法律秘书多久了
How long have you been a legal secretary?
到春天就二十四年了
24 years this spring.
-你干得好吗  -我干得很好
- You good at what you do? - I'm great at what I do.
那你明天开始上班
Then you start tomorrow.
你觉得怎么样
Well, what do you think?
-十二码吗  -必须是
- Size 12? - You know it.
我觉得棒极了
Then I think they're awesome.
你不会专门为了给我看鞋
You didn't come all the way down here
大老远跑来这里的
to give me your new shoe.
我告诉过你上百遍了
And I'm telling you for the hundredth time,
迈克尔不会离开耐克的
Michael is not leaving Nike.
这是我第一次  不是为了迈克尔而来
And for the first time, I'm not here about Michael.
阿迪达斯刚给我开出了一亿美元的价钱
Adidas just made me an offer for $100 million.
阿迪达斯可以去死了
Adidas can go to hell.
因为那只是你公司市值的三分之一
That's 1/3 of what your company's worth.
-哈维  我想接受  -什么
- Harvey, I want to take it. - What?
我不会让你这么干的
I'm not letting you do that.
我不是在求你许可
I'm not asking for your permission.
我不管  反正我不会让你
And I don't give a shit-- I'm not letting you sell
廉价把公司卖了
your company for pennies on the dollar.
你为什么要这么干
Where the hell is this coming from?
因为人生苦短
It's coming from the fact that life is short,
我累了  我准备好要向前看了
I'm burnt out, and I'm ready to move on.
人生苦短
Life is short?
这就是你不肯深思熟虑这件事的原因吗
That's your reason for not thinking this through?
我不想深思熟虑
I don't want to think it through.
我怕深思熟虑之后我会改变主意
I might change my mind and not do it at all.
好吧  泰迪  你想卖公司
Okay, Teddy, you want to sell?
那就卖  但我们白手起家建立了这家公司
Sell, but we built this company from the ground up.
给我一周时间帮你搞个更好的价钱
Give me a week to get you a better offer.
我给你的时间  与他们给我的时间一样
I'll give you the same thing they're giving me.
四十八小时
48 hours.
就这么定了
Then I'll take it.
顺便问一句  唐哪呢
By the way, where's Donna?
-她向前看了  -看
- She moved on. - You see?
这就是我所说的
That's what I'm talking about.
人生苦短
Life is short.
唐娜另谋高就
Donna moved on to something better.
她不是另谋高就
She didn't move on to something better.
什么意思
What do you mean?
她去为路易工作了
She's working for Louis.
利特吗  出什么事了
Litt? What the hell happened?
没出什么事
Nothing happened.
只是到了需要变动一下的时候
Just time for a change.
她去给那混蛋工作  肯定是出什么事了
If she's working for that asshole, something happened.
泰迪  你说你知道应该在什么时候做出改变
Teddy, you say you know when it's time to move on,
现在就是应该改变话题的时候了
it's time to move on from this topic right now.
好吧  哈维
Okay, Harvey.
我只是说外面那位大妈可替代不了唐娜
All I'm saying is Mrs. Keebler out there ain't no Donna.
连着两天见面
Twice in two days?
人们会说我们闲话的
People are gonna get the wrong idea.
他们爱怎么想怎么想
Well, they can think what they're gonna think,
但那可阻止不了我来给我的好兄弟
but it's not going to stop me from giving my boy
送订婚礼物
an engagement gift.
-你要给我一个案子  -不是随便一个案子
- You're giving me a case? - It's not just any case.
这正对你的胃口  行善做好事
This is right up your alley. Do-gooder lane.
-好吧  -听我说  迈克
- All right. - Listen, Mike.
这些人遇到不公正对待的唯一原因就是
These people got the shaft for one reason.
他们是穷人  没人在乎他们
They're poor, and no one gives a shit about 'em.
他们需要一个英雄  你就是那个英雄
They need a hero, and you're that guy.
你为什么不能当那个英雄
Why aren't you that guy?
我就是个英雄
Oh, I am that guy,
但你是那个马上要娶瑞秋・赞恩的人
but you're the one getting married to Rachel Zane.
差点害我被解雇的那个瑞秋・赞恩
The same Rachel Zane that I almost got fired,
然后你却给了我第二次机会
and then you gave me a second chance.
所以这就是你补偿我的方法吗
So this is your way of making it up to me?
听我说  迈克  和原告们谈谈
Listen, Mike, talk to the plaintiffs,
我保证  听完他们的故事
listen to their stories, and I promise you
一定会让你那颗悲天悯人的小心脏流泪的
it'll break your little bleeding heart.
谢谢你  吉米
Thank you, Jimmy.
不用谢
Yeah, you bet.
如果杰西卡不同意我办这个案子怎么办
What if I can't get Jessica to sign off?
那我就把这个案子拿回去
Then I'll just take the case back
改送你套酒具什么的
and get you a decanter or some shit.
所以大家都一致同意
So it's unanimous.
从今天开始  所有初年律师都必须
From now on, all first-years are required
达到两千八百个小时的计费工作时间
to bill 2,800 hours
而且还得自己带午饭
and bring their own lunches.
恭喜啊  路易
Congratulations, Louis,
新一代律师又乖乖被你压迫了
another generation of associates smacked into submission.
现在  恕我失陪
Now, if you'll excuse me,
我想这次会议我已经开完了
I think I'm done with this meeting.
哈维  拜托  我们还有新事项要谈
Harvey, please, we still have new business.
说到这个  我想提议
Speaking of which, I'd like to propose a change
对当前的薪酬计算方法进行调整
to the current compensation formula.
你说什么
Excuse me?
自从接管委员会以来
Well, since taking over the committee,
我仔细查看了我们的薪资结构
I've been evaluating pay structures,
我认为现在是时候
and I think it's high time that this firm
提高我们律所计时收费的权重了
put a larger emphasis on billable hours.
你还是好好管好你自己的事吧  杰克
Why don't you stick to the 48th floor, Jack?
看来你对我的提议有意见
I take it you have a problem with my proposal.
当然有意见
You're damn right I do.
我刚接手一件公司出售的案子
I just took on the sale of a man's company,
我的佣金完全是按合同比例收取的
and my entire fee is contingent-based.
因为你总是自行其是
Because you operate as your own entity,
而我们其他人却在为律所这个团队合作努力
while the rest of us are members of a team known as this firm.
不  是因为我为这个律所
No, because I bring in
带来了大笔的收入
a truckload of money for this firm.
就像我说的  哈维・斯佩克特永远都搞特例
Well, like I said, special rules for Harvey Specter.
好了  杰克  够了
You know what, Jack? That's enough.
现行薪资体系运行得很好
The current system works fine,
而且我不认为你应该用这样不尊重得口气
and I don't appreciate you speaking to Harvey
和哈维说话
in such a disrespectful manner.
-你耍我吗  -哈维  我很抱歉
- Are you shitting me? - Harvey, I'm sorry.
省了你的抱歉吧  路易  这次会议结束
Save your sorries, Louis. This meeting's over.
哈维  听我说  我可站在你这一边
Harvey, listen. I'm on your side.
是  我不用你站在我这一边  好吗
Yeah. I don't need you on my side, okay?
-我还有事忙  -等等
- I have shit to do. - Wait.
我还没说我的提案呢
I haven't even brought up my proposal yet
关于男厕所的那个
for the men's bathroom.
你想继续享受临时称霸王的感觉
You want to finish being king for a day?
随便你
Be my guest.
喝着你那加了五十块糖的咖啡
Enjoy your coffee and your 50 sugars,
尽情享受去吧  但我说了我还有事要忙
and go for it, but like I said, I have shit to do.
斯坦利是个好人
Stanley was a good man.
从没旷过一天工
Never missed a day of work,
努力赚钱养家
provided for his family.
他不应该落得这样的下场
He didn't deserve what happened to him.
具体发生了什么事
What did happen?
我告诉过另一个律师
Like I told the other lawyer,
他因为胸疼去医院看病
he went to the hospital with chest pains.
他们说他没事
They said it was nothing.
他还是一直喊疼
He kept complaining.
斯坦利从来不喊疼
Stanley never complained.
两天后他们让他出院了
Two days later they released him.
那天晚上斯坦利回到家睡觉
Stanley went to sleep in our bed that night.
然后就再也没醒过来
And he never woke up.
是的
No.
他再也没醒过来
He didn't.
你确定医院让他出院
Are you sure the hospital released him
是因为保险公司缩短了他的留院观察期吗
because the insurance company cut his stay?
他明明生病了  罗斯先生
He was sick, Mr. Ross,
他们却让他回家
and they just sent him home.
还有两百多个人
There are over 200 other people
都和他遭遇了同样的命运
who had the exact same thing happen to them.
你觉得这会是巧合吗
You think that's a coincidence?
不  我不这样认为
No, I don't,
所以我才在考虑复查这个案子
which is why I'm considering reopening this case.
那你还犹豫什么呢
So what's stopping you?
首先
Well, for one thing,
我想知道你之前的律师为什么要退出
I want to know why your other lawyer dropped out.
因为他们用尽各种手段对付他
Because they worked that man to the bone.
他差点失去自己的律所
He almost lost his entire practice,
但我听说你背后有一个强大有实力的律所支撑
but I was told that you're with a big, powerful firm.
是的
I am...
但我不确定我能说服他们
but I don't know if I'm gonna be able to
同意接手这个案子
get them to sign off on this.
那我们该怎么办
So what are we supposed to do?
你只要安心等待就行
You're supposed to sit tight.
-那是怎么回事  -你在说什么
- What the hell was that? - What are you talking about?
你心里清楚我在说什么
You know exactly what I'm talking about.
你在会上拂袖而去
You stormed out of the meeting
我们应该一起主持
that we were supposed to run together.
我没有冲出去  我走了出去
I didn't storm out, I walked out
因为你主持得烂透了
because you were doing a shitty job running it.
你在说些什么  我一直在支持你
What are you talking about? I had your back.
在你让那个小丑企图裁减我的薪水之后
After you let that clown come after my salary.
我没让他做任何事
I didn't let him do anything.
我力挺了你  然而你羞辱了我
I defended you, and then you smack me down,
然后我不得不推迟了一个
after which I had to postpone a presentation
我本来满腔热情想做的陈述
that I was very passionate about.
这是个洗手间  有时有味道是正常的
It's a bathroom, Louis. It smells sometimes.
你为什么不进去
So why don't you just go in there,
做人们正常人做的事  从我面前消失呢
do what people do in there, and get out of my face?
你知道吗  唐娜说得对
You know what? Donna was right.
我就不该尝试与你重修于好
I should have never tried to make things right with you.
-和我重修于好  -是的  哈维
- Make things right with me? - Yeah, Harvey.
我让杰克那样做  可以让他清楚自己的身份
I let Jack do that so that I could put him in his place
并向你证明我会支持你  但你意识不到
and show you that I had your back, but you can't see it
因为你太嫉妒我和唐娜了
because you're too damn jealous of me and Donna.
-你刚刚对我说什么  -你在嫉妒
- What did you just say to me? - You're jealous.
你知道吗  路易
You know what, Louis,
如果我真的对你们俩那么不满
if I was so upset about the two of you,
为什么我还在付她薪水
why am I still paying her salary?
扯淡  律所付她薪水
Bullshit. The firm pays her salary.
不是全部
Not all of it.
我把她从地检办公室带来的时候
You see, when I brought her over here from the DA's office,
杰西卡不肯雇用她  因为我只是个初级律师
Jessica wouldn't hire her because I was an associate,
所以我付她薪水
so I paid her salary.
我当上合伙人以后
And then I made partner,
我觉得她薪水不够高  所以我给她涨了薪
and I didn't think it was enough, so I paid her more.
一次又一次
And again and again and again.
所以我受够了你说我嫉妒
So I've had enough of you telling me I'm jealous.
唐娜不再为你工作了
Yeah, well, Donna doesn't work for you anymore.
她为我工作
She works for me, and the only person
这位  将是唯一会支付她薪水的人
who's gonna be taking care of her salary--this guy.
-你听见了没  -我不介意
- You got that? - Fine by me.
但你夸下海口前
But before you say that,
最好搞清楚你给自己揽下了什么
you better know what you're getting yourself into.
我当然知道我揽下了什么
Oh, yeah, I know what I'm getting myself into,
因为那样的女人是不能用金钱衡量价值的
because you can't put a price tag on a woman like that.
我要跟你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
让我猜猜
Let me guess.
你在洗手间和哈维聊了几句
You got into a pissing contest with Harvey,
他告诉你他在支付唐娜的薪水
he told you he's been covering Donna's salary,
你  自尊心作祟  承诺你会接过这一职责
you, out of pride, said that you were going to take it on,
现在你来打探你掉进了多大的坑
and now you're here to find out how much you're on the hook for.
-完全不是这样  -好极了
- Nothing like that. - Oh, good.
-那是什么事  -以上你所说的全部内容
- Then what is it? - Everything you just said.
-路易  -杰西卡  求你了
- Louis-- - Jessica, please.
-我就想看一眼数额  -好吧  路易
- I just want to see the number. - Okay, Louis.
你想看数额  给你
You want to see the number? Here's the number.
谢...  你妹啊
Thank y-- holy goddamn shit.
你确定没有不小心多加了个零吗
Are you sure you didn't accidentally add a zero?
我很确定
Yes, I'm sure.
律所能不能
Is there any way the firm can--
律所是不会多付她的
The firm is not going to pick this up.
哈维知道这一点  但依旧选择多付她薪水
Harvey knew that, and he chose to pay her more anyway.
那我要怎么办
What the hell am I supposed to do?
在我看来你有两个选择
Well, it seems to me you have two options:
你可以告诉唐娜哈维一直在补贴她的薪水
You can tell Donna that Harvey's been augmenting her salary,
但你不想继续这么做
and you don't want to do it anymore.
-不行  -或者你可以自己承担她的薪水
- Negatory. - Or you can pay it yourself.
-不可能  -还有第三个选择
- Not happening. - There is a third option.
我可以把她派还给哈维
I can send her back to Harvey.
你敢
How dare you?
什么叫我没法儿变现
What do you mean I'm not liquid?
谁喊你只留百分之十的现金的
Who told you to only save 10% cash?
我不管我说了什么
Well, I don't care what I said.
我说我有槌状脚趾的时候
Does my podiatrist listen to me
我的足病医生听我的了吗
when I tell him I have hammertoe?
一切都顺利吗  路易
Is everything okay, Louis?
-好极了  -好的
- Everything's wonderful. - Okay.
实际上  我突然想起来
Actually, it occurred to me
我们还没有讨论过一个很重要的议题
that we have not discussed a very important subject.
什么
What is it?
唐娜  钱是个很敏感的话题
Donna, money's a very sensitive issue.
我觉得你应该得到合理的报酬
And I think you should be fairly compensated.
我知道你为了我离开哈维是个艰难的决定
I mean, I know how hard it was for you to leave Harvey for me,
我永远都会心存感激
and I am forever grateful.
-只是我  -路易
- It's just that I-- - Louis, shh.
我不需要大幅涨薪
I don't need a huge raise.
标准的百分之二已经足够了
The standard 2% is more than enough.
-百分之二  -是的
- 2%? - Yes.
你很慷慨
You have a huge heart,
但我的薪水已经比律所其他秘书
but I already make more than every other secretary
都要高了  所以
at the firm, so--
-那就百分之二  -谢谢  路易
- 2% it is. - Thanks, Louis.
别客气
Don't mention it.
你现在有空吗
Hey, do you have a second?
我需要你的法律建议
I need your legal advice about something.
当然  什么事
Yeah, of course. What is it?
我的未婚妻把这份婚前协议落在厨房了
My fiance left this prenup in the kitchen.
你觉得我应不应该签字
I'm just wondering if you think I should sign it.
迈克  这不是看上去那样
Mike, it's not what it looks like.
看上去你父亲给你准备了一份婚前协议
It looks like your father had a prenup prepared
让我签字
for you to make me sign.
那么就是看上去那样
Then it's exactly what it looks like.
我猜你不想让我签字
And I'm guessing you don't want me to sign it?
不  我不想
No, I don't,
因为他总是想控制我的人生
because he's been trying to control me my entire life,
这次我不会让他这么做的
and I'm not gonna let him do that with this.
你有没有想过
Has it occurred to you
你父亲这么做只是因为爱你
that maybe your father is only doing this because he loves you?
我不在乎他为什么这么做
I don't really care why he's doing it.
好的婚姻不是从协议开始的
Great marriages don't start with contracts.
-我知道  -那你干嘛来拷问我
- I know that. - Then why are you grilling me?
因为你不告诉我这件事是有原因的
Because there's a reason that you didn't tell me about this,
我想知道是什么
and I need to know what it is.
我父亲说他不了解
My dad said he doesn't know the man
我想要嫁的这个人
that I'm choosing to marry,
我就是
and I just--
我不想对你说这些
I didn't want to tell you that.
-但我还是知道了  -是啊
- Well, I found out anyway. - Yeah.
瑞秋  以后
Rachel, in the future,
我希望你能
I want you to feel comfortable
放心地跟我说这些事
telling me this stuff in the first place.
我会的
I will.
斯佩克特先生  我想...
Mr. Specter, I wanted to--
你还没下班吗
You're still here?
你不下班我是不会下班的
I don't leave until you leave.
好吧  我和阿迪达斯的会面是几点
Well, in that case, what time is my meeting with Adidas?
11:15
11:15.
我把十一点的行程挪到下午三点
I moved your 11:00 to 3:00
三点的挪到了五点
and your 3:00 to 5:00.
-安排好...  -买家吗
- Did you line up-- - Buyers?
好了  但还需要一个星期
I did but not for another week.
耐克和彪马在海外
Nike and Puma are overseas,
你说过如果其他两家不能去
and you said Reebok didn't matter
锐步一家于事无补
if the other two can't be there.
该死
God damn it.
-还有一件事  -有区别吗
- There's one more thing. - What difference does it make?
不知道我的客户为什么一时兴起要卖公司
I can't delay the sale if I don't know
就不能拖延交易
why my client is dumping his company on a whim.
我要说的就是这件事
That's the one more thing.
道尔先生的挚友
Mr. Doyle's best friend died
一个月前因患胰腺癌去世了
a month ago of pancreatic cancer.
才46岁
He was 46.
你怎么知道
How'd you know that?
他在说我坏话之前
Something he said to you just before
跟你说的话
he started talking shit about me
让我很在意
stuck in my head.
什么话
What exactly was that?
当一个人在半分钟内两次说到"生命短暂"
When people say "Life is short" two times in 30 seconds,
一般是在某人去世以后
it's usually right after somebody died.
这么说你在听我们谈话
I take it you were listening to our conversation.
优秀的秘书都这么做
That's what good secretaries do.
-抱歉取笑了你  -又不是你说的
- Sorry about the Keebler thing. - You didn't say it.
而且  不是非得爱因斯坦才能弄清楚
Besides, it doesn't take Albert Einstein to figure out
你为什么会雇佣我这种丑八怪
why you hired somebody that look like me
来代替她那种美人
to replace somebody that look like her.
听着  格蕾琴  我...
Listen, Gretchen, I--
你不用跟我解释
You don't have to worry about that with me.
我喜欢我的男人爷们儿点
I prefer my men manly.
我不够爷们儿吗
Am I not manly?
你连这问题都得问的话...
Well, if you have to ask...
迈克  你好啊
Mike, how you doing?
罗伯特
Robert.
有事吗
What can I do for you?
我听说你想要我签署婚前协议
I heard you wanted me to sign a prenup.
没错
I did.
希望你别当我是针对你
I hope you didn't take it personally.
当然不会  我很愿意签
Of course not, I'm happy to sign it,
但是瑞秋说你不知道
but Rachel did say that you don't know
我是什么样的人
what kind of guy I am,
所以我觉得应该过来让你看看
so I thought I'd come here to show you that
这就是我的为人
this is the kind of guy I am.
你要对付凯尔顿保险公司
You're going after Kelton Insurance?
重要的不是我要对付谁
It's not about who I'm going after.
而是我要代表谁
It's about who I'm representing.
我要冒险为这二百人打官司
I'm putting my ass on the line for 200 people
除了我  没人愿意为他们做主
who have no one to fight for them other than me,
如果你担心一旦出了意外
so if you're worried that I'd go after Rachel's money
我会谋取瑞秋的钱
if something went wrong--
你不是那种人
You're not that type of guy.
不  我不是
No, I'm not.
我很钦佩
I respect that.
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
但让我告诉你件事
But let me tell you something.
我也曾是那些人中的一员
I used to be one of those people,
我摸爬滚打混到今天的地位
and I scratched and clawed my way to where I am today,
所以我清楚
which is why I know
当你从一无所有  变得有所成就
when you come from nothing and you make yourself into something,
你就总是等待着
you're always waiting for the day
别人会来把它取走的那天
they're gonna come and take it away.
我要告诉你  我也曾经一无所有
I'm telling you that I come from nothing,
我永远不会那么做
and I would never do that.
我不是说你会这么做
I'm not saying you're gonna take it.
我是说你会做某些事情
I'm saying you might do something
其他人会因此针对你
that makes someone else take it.
什么意思
What do you mean?
你在哈维・斯佩克特和杰西卡・皮尔逊的
You're learning at the feet of Harvey Specter
身边学习
and Jessica Pearson,
他们和我都清楚一件事
and they know something I know.
你会成为一名优秀的律师
You're gonna be a great lawyer.
你是做大事的人
You're gonna crack some eggs,
你永远不知道什么时候  会有人因为你做的事
and you never know when someone's gonna come at you
拿走属于你的东西
to take what's yours for something you did.
-罗伯特  我永远不会...  -让我说完
- Robert, I would never-- - Let me finish.
我跟你说这些  是因为你就要成为我的家人
I'm telling you this because you're gonna be family.
你也许还没越线  但总有一天会的
You might not have crossed any lines yet, but you will.
我只是想保护我的女儿
I'm just trying to protect my baby girl.
杰西卡  你想见我
Jessica, you wanted to see me?
其实是路易想见我们两个
Actually, Louis wants to see both of us.
那就有事说事吧
Then let's get it over with.
好的
Okay.
我想提议
I would like to propose
依照以下方针
a revamping of the pay structure
调整薪金结构
under the following guidelines.
我们提高合伙人的小时佣金抽成
We increase the percentage of billables the partners get.
通过抵消量来降低
We decrease the percentage of contingent fees
-胜诉酬金的抽成  -什么
- by an offsetting amount. - What?
这不是杰克・索罗夫昨天的提案吗
That's what Jack Soloff said yesterday.
不  这个不同
No, this is different.
我给合伙人的工资变动加了上限
I've capped the amount it affects any one partner.
你扯淡吧
You got to be shitting me.
我知道你们想知道我为什么这么提议
I know you're wondering why I'm proposing this.
理由清楚得很
It's crystal clear why you're proposing it.
你涨的工资刚好够付唐娜的薪水
You get the exact amount to cover Donna's salary,
还是从我这里刮来的钱
and you take it out of my paycheck.
-路易  -这和那事没关系
- Louis-- - This has nothing to do with that.
杰克的主意很棒
Jack had a great idea.
只是需要轻微调整
It just needed some fine-tuning.
轻微调整  是你说
Fine-tuning? You're the one that said
你让他提出来
you only let him bring it up
只是为了毙掉它
so that you can smack it down.
是真的吗
Is that true?
是  大概吧  但我考虑了一下
Yes. Maybe, but I had some time to think about it.
杰克提了建议
Jack put something on the table,
实现它是我们的责任
and it's our duty to follow through on it.
扯淡  你想实现它
Oh, bullshit--you're only following through on it
因为你是个狗娘养的小气鬼
because you're a cheap son of a bitch.
-哈维  -我不想听  杰西卡
- Harvey. - I don't want to hear it, Jessica.
昨天  他说我嫉妒他
Yesterday, he accused me of being jealous.
今天  他又想抢我的钱
Today, he's coming after my money.
-我没有  -闭嘴
- No, I'm not-- - Shut up.
我们都清楚唐娜去为你工作
We both know Donna going to work for you
不是因为你
has nothing to do with you.
-你走运而已  -走运
- You got lucky. - Lucky?
就像中彩票的猴子一样
Like a monkey who won the lottery,
所以你至少可以男人点  自己付账
so the least you can do is be a man, pay her yourself,
或者认怂  告诉她你付不起
or suck it up and tell her the truth.
够了  不要这样
All right. That's enough. We're not doing this.
-我是冠名合伙人  -路易
- I am a name partner. - Louis.
不  他没有权利
No. He has no right to--
你再不闭嘴我就动手让你闭嘴
I will slap the taste out of your mouth.
谢了  杰西卡
Thanks, Jessica.
感谢你站在我这边
I appreciate you being on the same page.
我才没站你那边
Oh, we're not on the same page.
你说什么呀
What are you talking about?
我昨天让你们俩去主持会议
I wanted the two of you to run that meeting yesterday
就是为了看你们能不能合作  但显然不能
to see if you were okay with each other, but you're not.
他也许是小气  但他没错
He may be cheap, but he's right.
你就是在因为唐娜的事拿他出气
You are taking your Donna anger out on him,
你不许再这样
and it needs to stop.
我才没因为唐娜的事生气
I don't have Donna anger.
说的跟真的一样
Oh, like hell you don't.
如果你再自欺欺人
And if you don't admit that to yourself,
我也会对你动手
I'll slap the taste out of your mouth too.
你在忙什么呢  迈克
What you working on there, Mike?
没什么  善后工作
Um, nothing. Just some cleanup.
有事吗  杰西卡
What can I do for you, Jessica?
我需要你告诉我你为什么
You can tell me why you reopened a case
重开了一个我们之前就没打算接的
against a major insurance company
起诉大型保险公司的案子
we were never a part of to start with.
我重开
Um, I reopened it
是因为我看了一眼觉得能赢
because I looked at it and it's a winner.
我也看了一眼
Well, I also looked at it,
我觉得赢不了
and I say it's a loser.
-杰西卡  -你接了个意外事故的案子
- Jessica, look-- - You took a case on contingency
原告还都是穷人
where every plaintiff is dirt poor,
也就是说就算赢了
which means, even if we win,
也是入不敷出
compensation for lost wages is nothing.
你没算惩罚性赔偿
You're leaving out punitive damages,
而且哈维天天都接意外事故的案子
and Harvey takes cases on contingency all the time.
他接那些是为了赚钱
Yeah, he takes them to make money,
不是为了救困在树上的小猫咪
not to save kittens in trees.
我也告诉你了这件能赚钱
And I just told you this is going to make money.
自由铁路公司的案子你也是这么说的
And that's what you said about Liberty Rail,
可你不但没赚钱
and instead of making money,
还差点害唐娜进了监狱
it almost ended with Donna behind bars.
这次不会有人入狱的
No one is going to jail for this.
没错  因为那需要很多资金支持
No, they're not, because it's going to cost a fortune to fund,
而我不打算把钱花在不大可能成功的事上
and I'm not laying out that kind of money on a long shot.
杰西卡  我向我自己保证了
Jessica, look. I promised myself that I--
我不管你向谁保证了
I don't care who you promised.
你没经过我的允许就接了这个案子
You took this case without running it by me,
而且你不问我就是因为知道我不会同意
and you did it because you knew I'd say no.
-杰西卡  -够了
- Jessica-- - So that's enough.
撤销  否则我去撤销
Dump it, or I will.
我得和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
是吗
Really?
上次你和我谈
'Cause the last time you talked to me,
你让我开口  然后又否决我
you told me to open my mouth, and you slammed it shut.
因为你想整哈维  但我现在愿意了
Because you wanted to go after Harvey, but now I'm on board.
-我凭什么相信你  -回答我
- Why should I believe you? - Answer me this.
如果我们投票的话
How many partners do you have in your pocket,
你能调动多少合伙人支持
if we put your proposal to a vote?
45%
I can get 45%.
你该相信我的理由就是
Well, then the reason you can believe me
我能帮你通过投票
is that I'm gonna get you the difference.
你自己的会议上你都不敢支持我
How you gonna do that if you don't have the courage
你又要怎么办到这事
to back my plan at your own meeting?
我会让律所的人都知道
By showing everyone at this firm exactly
哈维赚了多少
what Harvey makes.
这下我是确定你在骗我了
Now I know you're bullshitting me.
那样做你会被开除
You'd be fired if you did that.
如果是意外泄露就没问题
Not if I do it by accident.
你能相信吗  卖运动鞋
Can you believe that sneaker brings in
仅在中国就能赚到十亿
over a billion dollars from China alone?
这么高的收益让我不禁思考
With earnings like that, makes me wonder
你为什么还要坑我的委托人
why you're trying to rip off my client.
以合理的价格收购公司
Buying a man's company for a fair price
可不能算坑吧
is hardly ripping him off.
问题就是价格不合理
But it's not a fair price.
你给了我的委托人两天时间考虑
You gave my client 48 hours to take your offer.
我给你五分钟考虑我的提议
I'm gonna give you five minutes to take mine.
出双倍  否则我就走了
Double your money, or I walk out the door.
真是可笑
That's ridiculous.
可笑的是你去欺负一个
What's ridiculous is you preying on a man
刚刚失去了挚友的人
who just lost his lifelong friend.
我是商人  不是悲痛顾问
I'm a businessman, not a grief counselor.
那我就给你当回顾问
Then let me counsel you on this.
因为他正处于悲痛中  所以我有权
Because he's grieving, I have the ability
向董事会申请延后这个交易
to go to the board and delay this sale.
但你不会  因为你知道
But you're not going to, because you know
那样等他终于愿意卖了
it'll drive down the price even more
价格会更低
when he eventually wants to sell anyway.
没错  是会如此
You're right, it will,
但我告诉你  波克先生
but I'll tell you what, Mr. Polk,
就算那样也比你现在的出价高
it'll still be worth more than your offer.
而且等我的委托人从悲痛中走出来
And after my client's grief passes,
也许他还会想卖
he may still want to sell,
但绝对不会卖给你了
but it sure as hell won't be to you.
再联系
I got to call you back.
你怎么进来的啊
How the hell did you get in here?
开除你之后我立刻把艾米开除了的
I fired your assistant ten minutes after I fired you.
看来就算那样艾米也有办法放人进来
Guess Amy still knows how to get a person through.
恭喜
Congratulations.
你怎么进来就怎么出去吧
You made your way in. You can make your way out.
但首先我想给你个机会赚两千万
Not before I give you the chance to make $20 million.
你为什么觉得我会想卷入
What makes you think I want to get in the business
保险集体诉讼呢
of underwriting class-action lawsuits?
因为你想赚钱
Because you're in the business of making money,
在你拒绝以前我先说
and before you say no,
我可以给你20%的提成
I'm gonna give you 20% off the top.
这是上限了
It's the best deal out there.
不够
Well, that's not good enough.
25%
25%.
你有权做这个决定吗
Are you authorized to do that?
你没有
No, you're not.
以我对你的了解  他们可能都没批准你
Knowing you, you probably don't even have the authorization
直接来找我
to come to me in the first place.
我来找你是因为这能补偿我犯下的错误
I came to you because this is our chance to make it right.
一派胡言  你需要的是钱
Bullshit. You need money.
你站在我面前就为了这一个目的
That's the only reason you're standing here in front of me.
乔纳森  我可以找任何人
Jonathan, I could have gone anywhere.
我来找你与去找沃尔特・吉利斯是一个道理
I came to you for the same reason I went to Walter Gillis,
为了弥补错误
to make it right.
不信你打电话问他
Pick up the phone and ask him.
我不是沃尔特・吉利斯
I'm not Walter Gillis.
告诉艾米我谢谢她让你过了安保
Tell Amy I said "Thank you" for getting you past security,
因为我现在要联系所有投资银行家
'cause now I'm gonna call every investment banker I know
让他们别搭理你的提议
and tell them to pass on your offer
因为迈克・罗斯不值得信任
because Mike Ross can't be trusted.
这是什么
What the hell is this?
我不知道你在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
你知道  这是哈维最近三个案子的收益表
Yes, you do. This is Harvey's last three income statements,
我发现它们被放在复印机里
and I found them sitting in the copy machine.
唐娜  你得把它放回去
Donna, I need you to put that back where you found it,
你得马上放回去
and I need you to put it back now.
-我不  -这不是请求
- I won't do it. - That was not a request.
-这是命令  -我不管
- That was an order. - I don't care.
-我不会让你这么做的  -你看吧
- I'm not gonna let you do this. - See?
我就知道一有机会你就会
I knew that you would jump at the first opportunity
站在他那边对付我
you had to take his side over mine.
这不是我选择哈维
This isn't me taking Harvey's side.
而是我在阻止你犯大错
This is me stopping you from making a huge mistake.
要是他这么干  你肯定不会阻止他
And if he did the same thing, you wouldn't be stopping him.
哈维从不做这种事
Harvey would never do anything like this,
就算他做了  我也会阻止他
and if he did, I sure as hell would.
-胡说  -不  路易
- Oh, bullshit. - No, Louis.
我没胡说
It's not bullshit.
你根本不知道有多少次
You have no idea how many times
我让他别对你走极端
I kept him from going overboard with you.
-我一半工作都是在做这个  -你知道吗
- It was half my goddamn job. - Well, you know what?
你也没能每次都阻止他
You didn't stop him every time,
这次你也别想阻止我
and you're not stopping me this time.
把它给我
Now, give me that thing.
好吧  你不想放回去
Okay. Fine. You don't want to put it back?
-我自己去  -路易
- I'll do it myself. - Louis--
够了  唐娜  你知道吗
No. Donna, you know what?
是你主动为我工作的
You came to work for me.
你做决定的时候知道我是什么样的人
You knew who I was when you did,
你该作出决定了
so now it's time for you to decide.
你到底要不要站在我这边
Are you with me or not?
路易・利特
高级合伙人
虽然我不反对意料之外的惊喜礼物
While I'm not opposed to unexpected gifts on my desk,
但我更希望它们是巧克力做的
I do prefer if they're made of chocolate.
懂了
Got it.
下次我送你签好的婚前协议时
Next time I leave you a signed prenup,
肯定做成巧克力
it will be made of chocolate.
你为什么要签
Why did you sign it?
-我去见了你爸爸  -什么
- I went to see your dad. - You did what?
我想让他知道
I wanted to show him
他女儿要嫁的是个什么样的男人
what kind of man his daughter was marrying,
因为我希望他信任我
because I wanted him to trust me.
迈克  他不信任任何人  正因如此
Mike, he doesn't trust anybody, which is exactly why
所以我才对他的婚姻建议不感兴趣
I'm not interested in his marital advice.
但就像你说的
But like you said, I would appreciate it
将来你做这种事之前
if in the future,
跟我说一声  我会很感激的
you tell me if you're gonna do something like that.
你没错  我去之前应该告诉你
You're right, I should have told you before I went over there,
但我得说  虽然没让他信任我
but for the record, instead of getting him to trust me,
但我相信了他
I ended up trusting him.
-迈克  -瑞秋  听我说
- Mike-- - Rachel, listen to me.
我知道你认为他这么做是为了控制你
I know you think that he's doing this to control you,
但他觉得是在保护你
but he thinks he's doing it to protect you.
而我从没有过一个
And the truth is that I never had a father
为我做这种事的父亲  所以...
who could do something like that for me, so...
你应该试着去了解他的初衷
I think that you should try and see where he's coming from.
那是什么
What's that?
你的新价格
It's your new offer.
-价钱翻了一倍  -这是我的工作
- It's twice the money. - It's what I do.
所以我才付你这么多钱
And that's why I pay you so much.
我不是为了钱才这么做的  泰迪
I didn't do it for the money, Teddy.
我这么做是因为你被敲了竹杠
I did it because you were getting ripped off,
我不能坐视不理
and I'm not gonna let that happen to you,
无论情况如何
no matter what the circumstances.
你知道了
You found out.
你怎么不告诉我实情
Why didn't you tell me what happened?
因为我不希望你来阻止我
Because I didn't want you to try and stop me.
你还是可以来找我啊
You still could have come to me.
跟你说什么
And tell you what?
我七岁就认识的朋友
That my best friend from when we were seven died
突然死了吗
out of the blue?
我二十年没和他说过话了
I hadn't spoken to him in 20 years,
因为我们为了一个
because we got into a fight
我连名字都忘了的女人吵了一架
over some woman whose name I can't even remember.
我现在根本不在乎运动鞋生意
And now I don't give a shit about the sneaker business.
我会理解的
Well, I would have understood.
你会吗
Would you have?
哈维
Look, Harvey,
我很感激你为我做的事
I appreciate what you did for me.
如果我能重回商场  你永远是我的律师
If I'm ever back in business, you'll always be my lawyer.
我永远是你的朋友
I'll always be your friend.
-路易  你有空吗  -不知道
- Louis, do you have a second? - Oh, I don't know.
你现在又要喊我什么动物  鬣鳞蜥吗
What animal are you gonna call me now? An iguana?
我不会叫你绰号的
I'm not gonna call you anything.
我来是想冰释前嫌
I'm here because I want to put everything behind us.
我真幸运啊
Well, aren't I lucky?
路易  别这样
Louis, please.
你没错
You were right.
会议上我很混蛋  在厕所里也是
I was a dick in that meeting and again in the bathroom
在杰西卡那的时候也是
and again with Jessica.
我说了一些希望能收回的话
I said some things that I wish I could take back,
但我们已经做了很久的朋友了
but we've been friends with each other for a long time,
我不希望就这么断交
and I don't want to throw that away.
你是真心的吗
You really mean that?
是的
I do.
过来
Come here.
哈维  这感觉太好了
Harvey, this is amazing.
我从没想过你会来找我
I never thought you would come to me and--
-见鬼  -什么见鬼
- Oh, shit. - "Oh, shit" What?
我忘了件事  我得去易趣网竞价个东西
I forgot. I have to put a bid on an item on eBay.
-什么  -一个蒙古的
- What? - A Mongolian...
螳螂的钢琴伴奏芭蕾
praying mantis piano ballet.
和你聊得真开心  我得走了
Good talk. I have to go.
这是什么  这不是你该看的
What is that? You shouldn't be reading that.
这可是保密信息
That's privileged information.
你他妈从哪里搞来的
Where the hell did you--
见鬼
Oh, shit.
这是干嘛的
What's that for?
这是预付费用
It's a retainer.
我在寻求一些法律建议
I am looking for some legal advice.
我觉得你雇不起我
I don't think you can afford me.
不会花太久的  我只是想让你看看这个
It won't take long. I just want you to take a look at this.
你让迈克签了这个
You got Mike to sign this?
我爸干的
My dad did.
那你来找我干嘛
Then why are you coming to me?
因为你曾经说过你有个跟我一样的
Because you once told me that you have a father
父亲
just like mine.
我猜  你觉得罗伯特是在试着控制你
Let me guess, you think Robert is trying to control you?
他的确成功地使
He did manage to construct a situation
我生命中的两个最重要的男人
where the two most important men in my life
背着我做下关于我的决定
are making decisions about me without me.
你知道我是怎么想的吗
You know what I think?
我觉得这跟你父亲没关系
I think this has nothing to do with your dad,
而且你清楚这点
and you know it.
是迈克
Mike.
对  是迈克
Yes. Mike.
这才是你来找我的真正原因
That's the real reason why you're coming to me,
哪怕你告诉自己它不是
even though you told yourself it wasn't.
-这可以保护我  -是的
- It could protect me. - It could.
但也可以有别的作用
It could also do something else.
比如在无形中破坏我们的感情
Undermine my relationship.
相信我
Believe me.
我已经有过最深的感受
I learned that one the hard way,
这意味着你必须扪心自问
which means you need to ask yourself,
你究竟爱迈克有多深
how much do you really love Mike?
全心全意地爱  深爱
I love him all the way.
那就别签
Then don't sign it.
免费
On the house.
还有  瑞秋  就你父亲这个人来看
And, Rachel, as far as your father goes,
我和他并不是很对盘
he and I don't always see eye to eye,
但我确实尊敬他
but I do respect that man.
要说他跟我爸有像的地方  那就是
And if he is anything like my father,
尽管他有很多缺点
for all of his faults,
但他情愿死
he would take a bullet
也不会让他的宝贝女儿伤到一丝一毫
before he'd let anything happen to his little girl.
多谢了
Thank you.
来了
Uh, okay.
上次是我和哈罗德买单
Harold and I ponied up last time
因为情况比较特殊
because it was a special occasion,
但朋友  今晚你请
but tonight drinks are on you, my friend.
可以接受
That's fair.
虽然我很喜欢这份礼物  但吉米  还给你
As much as I appreciate it, Jimmy, I got to return the gift.
-什么  -是的
- What? - Yeah.
-我不能接这个案子  -不不不
- I can't take the case. - No, no, no.
什么叫你不能接这个案子
What do you mean you can't take the case?
杰西卡不会为工时花钱
Jessica won't lay out the money for the man hours.
那就让其他人出这笔钱好了
Okay, then get somebody else to lay out the money.
迈克  投资银行现在都在
Mike, investment banks are taking stakes
参与这些事情
in shit like this now.
所有人里  你该最清楚
You, of all people, should know that.
你觉得我没试过吗
You think I didn't try that?
我没有成功
It didn't work.
妈的  迈克
God damn it, Mike.
你总是说你是在乎那些人的
You always said you gave a shit about people.
你也说了我可以退回这个案子
And you said that I could return this case.
我不管我说过什么
I don't care what I said.
吉米
Jimmy,
到底发生什么事了
what the hell is going on here?
好吧  我叔叔基思也是受害者之一
Okay. One of the victims was my uncle Keith,
但我没告诉你是因为我表妹来找我
but I didn't tell you about him because my cousin came to me
让我好好处理
and asked me to make it right,
我也答应了她
and I promised her that I would.
但是  我在我们律所没什么发言权
It's just I don't have the juice at my firm,
我也
and I was--
我也很惭愧不敢告诉你
I was too ashamed to tell you.
-吉米  -迈克  听我说
- Jimmy-- - No, Mike, listen.
很抱歉我没跟你直说
Look, I'm sorry I didn't tell you straight up.
但是  求你了  这些人需要你的帮助
But, please, these people need your help.
杰克  我有什么可以帮到你的吗
What can I do for you, Jack?
你可以跟我解释下
You can explain to me
你怎么会挣到这么多钱的
how the hell you justify making this much money.
你是从哪儿拿到的
Where'd you get this?
它留在复印机里了
Was left in the copy machine.
-谁留下的  -我不知道
- By who? - I don't know.
但现在我知道你为什么
But now I do know why you pissed
对我开会时候提出的想法那么生气了
all over my idea at the meeting.
这可是保密文件
This is confidential.
曾经是
It was confidential.
现在  每个高级合伙人都看过了
Now, every senior partner's seen it,
而且大家都已经火冒三丈了
and people are furious.
我挣的每一分钱都是我应得的
I earn every penny I make.
那可不一定
We'll see about that.
你这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
我刚刚要求明天就我的提议进行投票
I just called for a vote tomorrow on my proposal,
希望你有存钱的习惯
and I hope you've been saving your money,
因为你那钱多事少的工作马上就要没了
because your gravy train's about to leave the station.
所以这就是你说"见鬼"的原因
So this is why you said, "Oh, shit."
不知道你在说什么
What's that?
你当然知道
Oh, you know what it is,
因为是你把它忘在
because you're the one who left it
复印机里的
in the goddamn copier.
天呐  哈维  我是在复印
Oh, my God, Harvey, I was making copies
每个人的工资单留档  我必须
of everyone's salaries for my records, and I must have--
放屁  路易
Bullshit, Louis.
你是为了打击我
You did this to come after me,
然后我道歉之后你想要阻止它
and after I apologized, you ran and tried to stop it.
哈维  求你了  事已至此
Harvey, please, what's done is done,
你也说了  我们是朋友
and like you said before, we're friends.
我们可以渡过这关的  我们也可以搞定投票
We can move past this, and we can fight the vote together.
大家看过之后  我不可能赢得投票的
There's no way I win the vote after people see this.
你想渡过这关是吗  那就去承认是你干的
You want to get past it? Admit what you did.
那我会被自动解约的
That's automatic termination.
然后我们再一起并肩作战
Then we'll fight that together.
-哈维  不行啊  -路易
- Harvey, I can't. - Louis!
杰西卡已经解雇过我一次了
Jessica tried to fire me once.
我不能让她有第二次机会再解雇我
I can't give her the chance to do that again.
你猜怎么着
Well, you know what?
你还会被解雇
It's gonna happen again,
因为我知道你做了什么
because I know what you did.
够了
You know what? That's enough.
你跑来对我咆哮指控
And you come at me flinging accusations,
那你最好有证据
well, you better have proof.
你有证据吗  哈维
You have proof, Harvey?
我看没有
Yeah, I didn't think so.
哈维  你不能再这么不分时间地
Harvey, you don't get to come to me
跑来找我了
at all hours of the night anymore.
我来是因为你的新老板
I'm here because your new boss--
-我知道你为什么来  -那你就知道他做了什么
- I know why you're here. - Then you know what he did.
我需要你承认
And I need you to admit it,
这样我就能阻止他们愚蠢的投票
so I can block their bullshit vote.
然后让路易被开掉吗
And get Louis fired?
如果你一开始就阻止他
He wouldn't be in this mess if you'd have just stopped him
他也不会陷入这种情况
from doing this in the first place.
哈维  如果我知道路易要做这样的事
Harvey, if I knew Louis was gonna do something like this,
我这么说意思不是我真知道
and I'm not saying I did,
我会当面让他不要做
then I would have told him to his face not to.
但如果他坚持要做
But if he went ahead and did it anyway,
我也不会背叛他来纠正这事
then I'm not gonna go behind his back to fix it.
因为你总说  "人一旦选择了立场
Because you always said, "Once you pick a side,
"就要忠于他的立场
"if you're not loyal to that side,
"不然他算什么人呢"
"then who the hell are you?"
那你在选择一个
Then you should have thought of that
会做出这种事的人之前
before you picked someone who would do something like this
就该好好想想
in the first place.
你想知道路易是什么样的人吗
You want to know what kind of man Louis is?
整件事情的起因就是他想证明
This whole thing started because he wanted to prove
他会给你支持
to you that he had your back,
因为他觉得你嫉妒我们
because he thought you were jealous of us.
不  整件事的起因是
No, this whole thing started
因为我告诉他从我们加入律所开始
because I told him that I've been paying your salary
就是我在付你薪水
since we came to the firm,
而他太小气  自己付不出
and he was too cheap to pay it himself
还软弱得不敢跟你说实话
and too weak to tell you the truth.
如果你把这件事瞒了12年
And if you've kept that from me for 12 years
而现在又说出来  那你可能真是在嫉妒
and you're only just telling me now, then maybe you are jealous.
迈克  你怎么进来的  她已经给你钥匙了吗
Mike, how'd you get in? Give you a key already?
没有  劳拉让我进来的  说你在这里
No. Laura let me in. She said you'd be back here.
我不知道为什么
I don't know why.
我想找点有味的东西吃
I'm trying to find something tasty.
结果这整间屋子里
There's not one damn thing that's bad for you
就没有一点不健康食品
in this entire house.
那我猜我没跟她说我给你带了这个
Then I guess it's a good thing I didn't tell her
是正确的
that I brought you these.
鸡块
Oh, chicken nuggets.
瑞秋自己做的
Rachel made them herself.
油炸的  不是烤的吧
Deep-fried, not baked?
请随意享用
You're welcome.
她签了婚前协议吗
She sign that prenup?
没有  但她送来这些是因为她想通了
No, but she sent those because she realized the prenup
婚前协议代表的是爱  不是控制
was about love, not control.
那我尊重她的选择
Then I respect her decision.
什么改变了她对我的想法
What changed her mind about me?
你想知道原因吗
You really want to know?
-想啊  -是杰西卡
- Mm-hmm. - Jessica.
不是吧  她说了什么
Oh, shit. What did she say?
我得知道那个秘密
I got to know that secret.
我不知道她跟瑞秋说了什么
I don't know what she said to Rachel,
但我知道她跟我说了什么
but I know what she said to me.
这才是你来这里的原因
So that's why you're here.
记得我跟你说过我要代理的那些人吗
You know those people that I told you I was fighting for?
杰西卡不愿意接这个案子
Jessica's not gonna go for it.
我明白
I get it.
要花太多钱  而回报又太少
Too much money to lay out for too little payoff.
但你说过你也曾是那些人中的一员
But you said you came from the same place as these people.
罗伯特  他们需要你这样的人为他们争取
Robert, they need someone like you to fight for them,
而我做不到
and I can't do it.
所以我请求你帮忙
So I'm asking you to.
你觉得这案子能赢吗
You think this case is a winner?
能赢
I do.
那你觉得我们一起做如何
Then what do you say we do it together?
你在这里做什么  路易
What are you doing here, Louis?
我发现你今早没来投票
I notice you didn't come to the vote this morning.
是没有  我在忙着跟客户联系
No, I didn't. I was busy closing a deal for my client.
我猜猜  你让他们回填销售日期到昨天了
Let me guess. You had 'em backdate your sale to yesterday,
这样钱就能按过去的薪资结构结算
so it falls under your old pay structure?
不  路易  那是你会做的事
No, Louis, that's something you would do,
因为我跟你不一样  我不在乎钱
because unlike you, I don't actually care about the money.
你要我相信那鬼话吗
You expect me to believe that?
我不管你信不信
I don't care whether you believe it or not.
我的薪酬包能说明我做了什么
My compensation package was about recognizing what I do.
钱只是结果
Money was just a consequence.
所以我才不介意跟唐娜分享
That's why I didn't mind sharing it with Donna.
-你出去吧  -不
- Now, get out. - No.
你必然在乎钱  因为那是唯一
You did care about the money, because it was the last thing
可以区别你我的东西了
you had that separated you from me.
-你说什么  -我成了冠名合伙人
- Excuse me? - I got name partner.
我得到了唐娜  这让你抓狂
I got Donna, and that drove you nuts.
所以你在会上打击我
So you shit on me at the meeting,
然后又假装道歉
and then you pretended to apologize.
我确实道歉了  路易
I did apologize, Louis.
我很爷们地去找你
I came to you like a man,
而之后我给你机会报答我的时候
and then when I gave you the chance to make it up to me,
你卡壳了  一如既往
you choked, like you always do.
那你现在怎么看我
Well, how you like me now?
因为你唯一保有的  就是你赚得比我多
Because the only thing you had left was that you made more.
现在你也不比我多了  我赢了
And now you don't, and I win.
你什么也没赢
You didn't win anything.
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我在说  无论你得到什么
I'm talking about the fact that no matter what you get,
你总是想要更多
you're always wanting more.
但总想要更多的问题在于
And the problem with always wanting more is
从你得到的那刻开始  它就是可以被夺走的
that the second you get it, it can always be taken away.
你无法逆转投票结果的
You're not reversing that vote.
我不是在说投票
I'm not talking about the vote.
我在说你最在乎的东西
I'm talking about what you value most.
没错
That's right.
也许今天明天不会发生
Might not happen today or tomorrow,
但它总会发生的  因为我会想办法
but it's gonna happen, because I'm gonna make it happen.
某天  你会走进办公室
One day, you're gonna walk into your office,
发现她不见了
and she's gonna be gone.